[
  {
    "id": "q14",
    "question": "In which country was there a Bukharian First Lady (in 2003-2016)?",
    "options": [
      "Iceland",
      "The Netherlands",
      "Finland",
      "Greenland"
    ],
    "correct": "Greenland"
  },
  {
    "id": "q9",
    "question": "What country has the largest current population of Bukharian Jews?",
    "options": [
      "United States of America",
      "Canada",
      "Kazachstan",
      "Israel"
    ],
    "correct": "United States of America"
  },
  {
    "id": "q2",
    "question": "What year was the first Hebrew edition of \"Hebrew of the Bukharian Jews\" published in Israel?",
    "options": [
      1991,
      1985,
      2010,
      1971
    ],
    "correct": 1971
  },
  {
    "id": "q16",
    "question": "Are Bukharian Jews considered Sephardic, Mizrahi or Ashkenazi?",
    "options": [
      "Conservative",
      "Sephardic",
      "Mizrahi",
      "Ashkenazi"
    ],
    "correct": "Sephardic"
  },
  {
    "id": "q6",
    "question": "What is the name of a rice based dish that is colored green often by cilantro, dill, and/or parsley?",
    "options": [
      "Borsh",
      "Halti Svo",
      "Plof",
      "Bahsh"
    ],
    "correct": "Plof"
  },
  {
    "id": "q5",
    "question": "When did Hizkiah haCohen Rabin become the Chief Rabbi of Bukhara?",
    "options": [
      1889,
      1890,
      1896,
      1880
    ],
    "correct": 1880
  },
  {
    "id": "q17",
    "question": "How do you say bread in Bukharian?",
    "options": [
      "Zhon",
      "Pon",
      "Non",
      "Bon"
    ],
    "correct": "Non"
  },
  {
    "id": "q10",
    "question": "What city is best known for having been located on the Silk Road?",
    "options": [
      "Samarkand",
      "Bukhara",
      "Moscow",
      "Tashkent"
    ],
    "correct": "Samarkand"
  },
  {
    "id": "q18",
    "question": "Which country does NOT have a Bukharian Community today?",
    "options": [
      "Austria",
      "Moldova",
      "Australia",
      "Albania"
    ],
    "correct": "Austria"
  },
  {
    "id": "q7",
    "question": "What traditionally triangle shaped pastry is filled with pumpkin?",
    "options": [
      "Pelmeny",
      "Bichak",
      "Gorshgigeh",
      "Samsa"
    ],
    "correct": "Bichak"
  },
  {
    "id": "q8",
    "question": "What traditional dish is cooked in a bag is typically served after Shabbat service on Saturday?",
    "options": [
      "Bahsh",
      "Halti Svo",
      "Plof",
      "Babaganush"
    ],
    "correct": "Plof"
  },
  {
    "id": "q1",
    "question": "What year was \"Musa Namah\" written?",
    "options": [
      1326,
      1436,
      2018,
      1536
    ],
    "correct": 1326
  },
  {
    "id": "q12",
    "question": "The burning of this herb is said to protect from the evil eye;",
    "options": [
      "Olefiyosh",
      "Espondut",
      "Esranut",
      "Ookropp"
    ],
    "correct": "Olefiyosh"
  },
  {
    "id": "q11",
    "question": "Which city is the capital of Uzbekistan?",
    "options": [
      "Navoi",
      "Samarkand",
      "Kiev",
      "Tashkent"
    ],
    "correct": "Samarkand"
  },
  {
    "id": "q3",
    "question": "What year did the Manghit Dynasty come to power in Bukhara in the beginning of a massive conversions to Islam?",
    "options": [
      1788,
      1753,
      1891,
      1791
    ],
    "correct": 1753
  },
  {
    "id": "q4",
    "question": "What year was the first Bukharian-Jewish newspaper \"Rahamim published in Kokand, Uzbekistan?",
    "options": [
      1925,
      1910,
      1923,
      1914
    ],
    "correct": 1923
  },
  {
    "id": "q15",
    "question": "What is one language that had a significant impact on the Bukharian language?",
    "options": [
      "Azerbaijani",
      "Farsi",
      "Ukranian",
      "Russian"
    ],
    "correct": "Russian"
  },
  {
    "id": "q13",
    "question": "How do you say grandma in Bukharian?",
    "options": [
      "Bobo",
      "Baba",
      "Bebe",
      "Bebo"
    ],
    "correct": "Bebo"
  }
]